A Guide to the Walter Lloyd Fontaine Papers, 1813-1870
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Walter Lloyd Fontaine Papers, 1813-1870
The Library of Virginia
37818
38 pages
Walter Lloyd Fontaine
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 23 June 2000, L and T Respess Books, Charlottesville, Virginia.
Biographical Information
Walter Lloyd Fontaine (1787-1860) was the son of Abraham (1757-1831) and Sarah Ballard Fontaine (1762-1825) of Charles City and Goochland Counties, Virginia. He married first G. Nicholas and second M. F. Nicholas. With his second wife he had a child named Walter Scott Fontaine (b. 1826). Walter Lloyd Fontaine moved often both in Virginia and out-of-state. Records list his occupation as both an attorney and a farmer.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1813-1870, of Walter Lloyd Fontaine (1787-1860), an attorney and farmer of Buckingham, Goochland, Greenbrier Counties, and Williamsburg, Virginia, and Kentucky and Tennessee, consisting of receipts, invoices, letters, promissory notes, and a bill of sale. The documents principally concern Fontaine's legal involvement in estate administration and settlement. Fontaine family members comprise the majority of estates settled. There also is material relating to slave sales.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Walter Lloyd Fontaine Deed of sale, 17 Jan. 1817 (LVA accession 37813).
Contents List
- Promissory note, 13 Nov. 1813, of Walter L. Fontaine issued by Read & Robertson of Nelson County, Virginia.
- Receipt, 1 March 1814, issued to Walter L. Fontaine by the Cumberland County Clerk for taxes.
- Receipt, 10 April 1817, issued to Fontaine & Anderson by John Fox for the purchase of tobacco.
- Letter, 1 Nov. 1817, from M.S. Robinson to Walter L. Fontaine.
- Receipt, 6 May 1819, issued to Walter L. Fontaine by John McCormack.
- Receipt, 12 Oct. 1819, issued to Eli Totwilar by Walter L. Fontaine.
- Receipt, 1820, issued to John Ware on behalf of Fontaine & Quarles by the Fluvanna Circuit Court for various court fees.
- Receipt, 26 Jan. 1821, issued to James L. Cox by Walter L. Fontaine. 9) Receipt, 1822, issued to Walter L. Fontaine by Galt & Johnson of Richmond, Virginia.
- Receipt, 1822, issued to Walter L. Fontaine by Galt & Johnson of Richmond, Virginia.
- Receipt, 24 June 1822, issued to Walter L. Fontaine, executor of David Ross' estate, by Richard Wyatt, executor of John Ware's estate.
- Receipt, 1823, issued to Walter L. Fontaine, administrator of William Toney's estate, by the clerk of the Buckingham Superior Court.
- Receipt, 1823, issued to Walter L. Fontaine, administrator of William Toney's estate, by the clerk of the Buckingham County Court.
- Letter, 15 Dec. 1824, from John Thompson of Nelson County, Virginia to Colonel Walter L. Fontaine.
- Receipt, 1824, issued to Walter L. Fontaine, administrator of William Toney's estate, by the clerk of the Buckingham County Court.
- Receipts, 1823-1825, issued to Walter L. Fontaine, administrator of William Toney's estate, by the sheriff of Buckingham County.
- Receipts, 1825, issued to Walter L. Fontaine, administrator of Elizabeth Kidd's estate, by the Buckingham County Court clerk and sheriff.
- Receipt, 1825, issued to Walter L. Fontaine, administrator of Finch Scruggs' estate, by the clerk of the Buckingham County Court.
- Deed of sale, 5 Nov. 1825, for the purchase of two slaves by Walter L. Fontaine from Benjamin M. Perkins.
- Letter, 12 Sept. 1826, from Richard Harkney to James Fontain concerning an unpaid debt.
- Letter, 12 Feb. 1827, from Samuel Smithson (b. 1783) of Campbell County, Virginia to Colonel Walter L. Fontaine.
- Receipt, 1830, issued to Edmund Fontaine (1801-1869) by Clement Rush Fontaine (1791-1851).
- Receipt, 28 Aug. 1847, issued to Walter L. Fontaine by Sid. Grady of Richmond, Virginia.
- Promissory note, 1865, of Miletus B. Brown (b. 1815), administrator of Catharine Maury Fontaine's estate, issued by Walter Scott Fontaine (b. 1826) and C.R. Fontaine.
- Receipt, 6 Sept. 1867, issued by G.L. Peyton & Company in Greenbrier County, West Virginia for payment of a debt incurred by Catharine Maury Fontaine (b. 1784) and Walter L. Fontaine.
- Receipt, 30 May 1868, issued to M.B. Brown, administrator of Catharine Fontaine's estate, by John S. West & Co.
- Letter, 25 Oct. 1870, from William Fontaine (b. 1785) in Pittsylvania County, Virginia to M.B. Brown.
- Receipt, no date, issued to Walter L. Fontaine by Samuel Jones for the purchase of slave.
- Invoice, no date, of Alexander Roberts, administrator of T. Roberts estate, due to Walter L. Fontaine.